Mark Sikaundi | Computer Science

Location: Lusaka, Zambia Phone number:+260776578583 Email: <u>sikaundimark@gmail.com</u>

PROFESSIONAL PROFILE

Professional and creative as computer programmer and software developer with a track record of developing websites, android applications, graphic designing in the IT industry related field. I have delivered good services as a freelance in IT/Networking field with various organizations from Upwork.

With several years in the industry of IT/Networking, I have amassed a wealth of experience across different areas in the industry. My dedication in the services has landed me with different companies to have projects with. And am proven in my ability to be efficiency to work in the industry.

CORE SKILLS

- ♦ Web developer
- ◆ Android developer
- ◆ Programming Languages(python, JavaScript, Django & React)
- ♦ WordPress
- ◆ Freelancer
- ◆ Hardware/software troubleshooting
- ♦ Electronic Repair
- ◆ Microsoft office suits
- ◆ Google suits
- Data Entry
- ◆ Information management
- ♦ Information system
- ◆ Instructor
- ♦ Web scraping
- ◆ Computer forensic & security
- ◆ Linux server admin
- ◆ Writer
- ♦ Inventory management

CAREER SUMMARY

2017 present Holy Family Catholic Sisters Missionary School

Outline

Acting electronic maintenance assistant-the role was for taking cares of all the electronics devices from the security cameras, computers, televisions, printers, photocopying machines to make sure all are functioning and if anything need to be repaired was accountable and make sure its done professionally.

2019 Currently Up-work INC Freelancing Company USA

I have done quite number of small jobs from up-work as a freelancer from different clients around the world, both short term and long term. My Up-work profile is verified and it under the category of IT/Networking. I have carried roles with Indian's companies for Android development, Russian clients for android development and Canadian's clients coaching and helping them with computer science projects work. Also worked with a Dubai client developing a job search website a 3months contract.

2021-02-04 present Sonny sangha-United Kingdom

10days of Netflix clone internship participant for developing netflix movie streaming web application with full functionalities.

2021-04-07 present Pezajob Zambia

This was my 3months internship of developing a website for the company, with some different tools involved in it. It was a 3moths internship program. This was a collaborative with different people from Zimbabwe and Nigerians

2021-08-04 Present Sonny Sangha-United Kingdom

5Days of Airbnb challenge internship with a developer company based in the united kingdom to develop the Airbnb web application with a full package and functionalities.

2021-06-04 present Jobskaleej United Arab Emirate(Dubai)

Website developer for the job search and post, a 3months project, for building and debugs while on the server.

EDUCATION BACKGROUND

- ◆ 2020 2022: Chalimbana University computer science.
- ◆ 2019-2020: Muchigan university Advanced Python certificate
- ◆ 2016 2018: Broadway Secondary, General School Certificate.
- ◆ 2012 2013: Chowa Basic school, Junior secondary Certificate.
- ◆ 2005 2011: Mwashi Basic school, Primary school certificate.

LANGUAGE

English, Namwanga & Bemba

HOBBIES

- Coding(computer programming)
- Reading books
- Computer games

REFFERENCES

Mr. Tembo Training manager: +260 96 6275799

SR. Leah HOLY FAMILY CATHOLIC SUPERIO: +260 97 4225729

Upwork.com/marksikaundi

Github:https://github.com/marksikaundi

Linkedin:https://www.linkedin.com/in/mark-emmanuel-sikaundi-123a5

5198

Portifolio:https://sikaundimarkresume.netlify.app